So these default arguments are very, very helpful. One thing I want to cover before we move on from arguments is
something that trips up beginners and Python quite a bit. Don't use mutable types as default
arguments. They don't behave the way that you expect.
So if I have a function and I want to have a default argument with a list.
And say, a pen this string to my list. When I call it, when I call this function the first time,
oops. Sorry, I want to go ahead and return that.
So that we can actually see what happens. When I call it for the first time,
it does the right thing. When I call it a second time, there's now two instances of stuff in this
list and then three and then four. Do now use mutable arguments for defaults because the
way that Python works under the hood is these get declared once. So with you do this,
you are going to continue using that very same instance of my list. Every time you call that function,
even though that is not what you intended to do. So this is the source of a lot of subtle
bugs for beginners. So remember, no mutable default arguments. The way that you would want to do this
instead is to have a have a placeholder here where you're using a non-value as a placeholder.
And I'm going to introduce some concepts we haven't talked about yet, but then you can just say
if I've passed an a list, then use it otherwise you can say, if not my list, which means
if it's, if it's, I'm sorry, you want to say, if my list is equal to none, then make a new list
here and then append to it.
Now, when I call do stuff, it's going to do the right thing each time because I took care of
creating the list in this function. I did not pass in an empty list as a keyboard argument.
Wanted only append stuff in the case where my list isn't the file?
Yes. Yeah, just a silly little example.
So, right, I would want to move this over one to the left so that this example worked
when I did pass in a list to start with. Good catch, thank you.
Cool. So, these are arguments and I want to talk about scope a little bit.
There is scope inside of a function. So, I'm going to exit my
Ripple and start it from scratch to clear out everything that I might have defined already.
If I have a function that takes a name and prints it,
I cannot access this name variable outside of the function, outside of this
indented zone because the name is only defined inside of the function.
Once the function exits, that variable doesn't exist. So, Python scope works pretty similar to
scope and other languages. This is something you want to be mindful of.
You want to be very careful when you're using variables inside of a function that are defined
outside of it because if you try to change the value of that variable inside of the function,
the value is only going to apply for that scope. When your function exits,
you're not actually going to be able to modify the value of the variable defined
outside of the function. This can result in some weird subtle bugs. So, here's an example.
And I can say prints out the name outside of the function.
And then I'm going to make a method that says try to change the name.
And I'm going to say that name in the function is max
and print out names inside of the function.
Now, if I call this method, try change name. The name inside of the function is max,
but the name outside of the function is still Nina. So, don't try to change variables in a
function that were declared outside of it. You will have access to them, which can be helpful
if you have like a global variable defined that is like a URL or something that's static,
that's not going to change, but don't try to update it. You're going to end up with some weird
scopeing issues. And so, a use case for using a variable in a function that's decided to
find outside of it is a constant. And to delineate that it's a constant, in that case,
you can name it with all uppercase characters split with a underscore. And that's just
convention. It doesn't mean that there's anything different about that variable.
It's just named a little bit differently in order to signify something to the readers of the program.